

CONTACT

SUMMARY

I am a web developer who seeks adventure, from the ocean to the golf course. With 5+ years sales experience, I look forward to using my problem solving and critical thinking skills to help create meaningful things. I am excited to bring new ideas to the development world.

SKILLS

LANGUAGES: Ruby, JavaScript, jQuery, SQL, HTML, CSS / SASS, ActiveRecord, Git

FRAMEWORKS / SERVICES: Rails, Sinatra, Git Work Flow, Heroku, RSpec, Capybara, Jasmine, Pair Programing

PROJECTS

Loopi - www.loopi.run

Loopi is a web app created out of a desire to take the monotony out of running while also making it more efficient. It allows users to quickly and easily receive a random route loop where the start and end points are the same. We created Loopi for our 8-day team project at Dev Bootcamp.

- Rails-backed application
- Utillized Google Maps API with JavaScript for in application map manipulation
- Integrated Ruby Geokit gem and executed route randomization algorithm in collaboration with four team members

Making Hunger - www.makinghunger.com

Making Hunger is a simple web application that allows users to find, favorite and comment on recipes. This group project was completed in a day and a half.

- Rails-backed application
- Ruby BCrypt gem
- · First time using a third party API

EDUCATION

College of Charleston

Bachelor of Science Business Administration 2010

Relevant Courses - Computer Programming, Adobe inDesign, HTML/CSS, Computers Music and Art, Accounting, Economics, Business Law, Marketing, Finance, Management

AWARDS

Most Valuable Team Player

• Voted most valuable team player by colleagues in 2011

Northeast Region Certified Pre-Owned Sales Contest

 Exceeded sales goals by the greatest number of units while keeping a customer satisfaction rating above 95% for both 2012 and 2013

EXPERIENCE

Dev Bootcamp San Diego, CA

Web Development Student · Dec 2015 to Apr 2016

- Completed a 19-week intensive course comprising 1000+ hours of code learning Ruby, Rails, Javascript(JQuery,AJAX), Git, SQL, HTML5/CSS3, and accompanying tools and frameworks.
- The program culminates with a team project, an 8-day capstone. We focused on agile development, version control, iterative software practices, and empathetic communication.

MMCO Auto

Audi Porsche Conshohocken, Audi Wynnewood

Parts Manager · Apr 2015 to Jun 2015

- Managed all aspects of parts supply chain, including product ordering, high turnover inventory management, and product sales
- Collaborated across departments to achieve 100% of business plan each month
- Led team of six parts staff to inventory and track orders
- Solved team personnel issues, completed performance reviews
- Became top seller for Porsche and Audi accessories on Amazon and EBay

Assistant Parts Manager · Mar 2014 to Mar 2015

- Assisted parts manager in establishing department at a new dealership branch
- Oversaw team of four sales representatives, assisting in retail, wholesale, and online sales
- Prepared and tracked monthly budget to track goals

Inventory Manager · Jul 2011 to Mar 2014

- Researched to appraise inventory, assessing factors such as supply, age, and geographic market
- Managed inventory of an average of 40 vehicles per month valued over \$600,000
- Posted all pre-owned vehicles for sale online, including pricing, photos, and description (dealer website, manufacturer website, cars.com, autotrader.com, EBay Motors) resulting in growing business unit by 300% year over year

Audi Brand Specialist · Jun 2010 to Jul 2011

- Sold vehicles directly to customers in highly competitive Northeast Market
- Handled all aspects of sales, including lead generation, negotiation, leasing, financing, and delivery
- Maintained a 5-star customer rating on dealerrater.com